OK. So I think you can see my screen, right?
And you can see this announcement. I've also put through the Canvas announcement and you
should receive an email about this announcement and then which is about your
Azure VM account. So if you haven't got your Azure VM account,
please write to um Xiao Qing here and then
with this subject so that we will collect all the late enrolled
student information together, um. And then we can recreate another um
bunch of accounts, OK. So, but, I think
if you enroll before last Thursday, you should have um got the,
um, got the invitation. So please just register your account,
and then that should be OK, um, for you to start your
week two workshop, OK, to do some practice.
Now today we will talk about cyberattacks.
Um, and our product recording, um, if you have watched,
um, we have talked about software threats and network
attacks, right? Um, but if you haven't watched for this week,
it's OK, but I hope in the future weeks because the pre-lec recording,
uh, meant to be watched before the lecture,
because I may just introduce some, um, some
Some, some applications based on those algorithms already included in
my product recording. Otherwise, when you didn't watch your product recording,
watch, or you, you come to my lecture directly,
you may find, oh you, you, you, you, you get lost.
OK. But for this week, it's OK because these are just parallel content and
which doesn't really interconnect with um It
has too much. So if you haven't watched and watched after this lecture.
And we have talked about software threats and network attacks.
And today we'll focus on web attacks and hardware threats.
OK? So the objective for this week's study is to understand all
different types of cyberattacks and understand how those happen.
And, of course, some, some strategy to defend
these attacks, OK? So this is about brief history,
about all these cyber attacks. So the very early
one is, yeah, can be that early. So that's a whistle.
Um, the people use the high tone from the whistle to get long
distance free call, OK, back to 1971.
Um Of course, very special high tone, OK,
from that whistle. So that's a very, very first,
um, I mean, form of this cyberattack through this
telecommunication network, right? And then the very
well known one should be this Morris worm,
Morris worm, which was created by a student in that time.
And then now that very first piece of worm has been stored in the
um museum in America, right? Um, and
it has been, um, I think with that one, it has
actually infected, um, 2000 Unix
machine, OK, within 15 hours after it's launched.
Right. So this is about that time and all these popular names you
may have heard, and I myself actually was infected
by this one, back to my university period.
I've got this one infected in my computer and also some of
my classmates also got that infection through this email,
um, transmission. I mean, I mean, um.
So email attachment, right? Um,
And we probably will talk about the dirty cow at a later stage and how
that happens and how bleed is relevant to some internet protocol,
right? And then you can see those things,
uh, while those things happens, right? And shellshock,
yeah, again, it's very relevant to software,
uh, malware type of thing, so it's just that because of some uh
scripts which were not maintained very well and then that caused big issue,
right? So which is why the software security itself um can
be a course which is very heavily reliant on your programming
uh skill. And then if you know how to sanitize your code and you
will avoid all those problems. OK. But those attacks,
OK, those malware actually were created because of the,
some simple, um, scripts issue, OK. So this is
a very popular. Um, different types of malware.
Malware is actually short for malicious software,
and then there are different types which are all relying on this,
this software, um, code, code. And then,
so we have the, these popular names and then we just simply
go through all of them. Um, maybe you can have a read,
maybe when you have time, um. Uh, yeah, I won't probably just
read them, uh, out, and you can watch these words by yourself.
And interestingly, we have talked about the Trojan horse in our,
um, production recording, and spyware can be,
um, a particular type and also otherware can be a particular type which,
uh, belongs to this Trojan horse, right?
And then the spyware, which is to spy on people,
the people's behavior, and may spy on their keystroke,
um, and other covert, covered, um, payloads.
The other, otherware is especially targeted at some advertising.
And track users' behavior so that they can do more
targeted um analysis and advertising so that the person will
always be tricked to do something because um this adware has already
analyzed that person and know that person very well and know what kind
of particular product he would be interested,
right? So we call that adware. And then there's a keylogger,
um, especially targeted at the keystroke,
right, in the software. And then, then they can,
once your computer is infected, your computer's key,
um, behavior will all be recognized and remembered,
and then your credit card and password information will be,
um, stolen and by those keylogger uh malware.
And botnet is a Is some software robot which
can control a group of computers, uh, and then launch
large payload so that to create burden to a particular
computer. And then if that computer, computer is a server,
which means that server will be kept. Super busy,
and he can't respond to any other requests.
So that's why the botnet um is trying to target at
those big company server, right? OK, so
that's all different popular name of this,
um, Malware And then let's look at, by
combining different types of malware, there might be blended threads,
OK. The blended threads, here is one example,
just show you one example. There are many different types of blended threads.
So this is just one of them. So this one,
why I chose this one because this one is quite popular,
um, back in, uh, back to 2018, and it's still very
popular nowadays, OK. Um, it will go around our Facebook
and social media, uh, cycle, and sometimes you get some,
uh, links, and pop up to your Facebook account from
your friends, right? And you thought it's from your actual
friend, OK, uh, sharing, but actually it's not,
right? It's just some fake, um, link and
I mean, illegal link sometimes and to your,
to your site. And if you just, uh, I mean,
without awareness and just accidentally click them,
uh, what would happen would be very serious.
OK. So this is what it will do um by
this basic one, which is still nowadays very popular attacks in our
cyberspace. And then, so you get some link,
uh, some malicious link, um, was popped to your account,
um, through Facebook Messenger. And if you click those links,
and you will be, OK, it might be just some YouTube link,
right? And it, of course, it's not legitimate YouTube link.
And then, and then you will be redirected to a fake YouTube
page. And then at the same time, there will be faceworm
installed in your Google Chrome uh uh
extension. Right. And then, um,
After its installation, what happens in the back end is
your phone or your computer um will
communicate with a remote server. We call that
um CNC server, CNC command and control, command and
control server. So what it means is, the remote server will
be able to send some commands to your computer.
And then to do some control on your computer.
So we call that command and control server,
OK, which is remotely working, and then,
And then your computer will be downloaded some malicious JavaScript.
So this is what could happen with that command and control process.
So some JavaScript, such as the crypto uh currency
miner scripts will be launched to your computer and,
um, and you may, you may be redacted to some scam web
page and your credential may be stolen. And then some
transaction you were not aware will be acted on behalf on your
behalf, and then you will be reducted to some other
um programs, right? So this is what may happen through this
command and control um server and also
your computer through those remote communication,
OK, without your awareness. And then at the same time,
What would that face worm do is to send
malicious link to your friends, OK, your Facebook contact,
OK? And then your friends, when they see.
Uh, there's a link shared by you, and then they saw you just sharing some funny video,
and then they will just click the link and then they,
what you, what your friend's computer. I mean,
would do is again the same cycle as this.
So, this has been going around since 2018 and still
going around nowadays, and it, it's a very effective uh worm,
I mean, affecting, of course, it's called a worm because it has this self-propagation,
um. Capability and which we, we always name that
worm, right? But of course it has combined some other
um virus such as some crypto miner. It can be a virus just
launched to um your computer and then maybe only when you
click something and then it will be, I mean,
start infecting, right? Um, like this link and put
somewhere. And then, yeah, some, some virus,
OK, attached to those links, right? So, it's a blended threads.
And also in this blended threads, you can see the social engineering has been done because
when it says socially engineered, which means maybe not every,
um, yeah. Your, your Facebook user
or or contact will be popped up with this and sometimes it will
be more targeted at those users who have crypto uh currency
visiting behavior. So sometimes they just try to do,
try to decide what to launch after they have done some analysis
on you or on your friends, right? So. We,
we would call that a blended thread. OK.
There are many other types of blended threads nowadays,
uh, which can launch more harmful malware,
OK, through this blended threads. And then with this one,
you can see the two main property, I mean,
two characters here. One is targeted at cryptocurrency.
Actually they tried to steal the cryptocurrency.
And then the other one is just uh, it spreads through Facebook Messenger,
right? And which is very popular nowadays as a social
media um application, right? And then, also
other thing I'd like to mention here is why these blended
threads always pop up and every year, even every month,
and then those malware, the new malware always get
some um Like
Benefit from these people or from the market,
because there is a cycle actually for this malware to
be created and then launched to the market and the
It's very similar to the coronavirus, if you still remember,
and those virus keep evolving itself and then will be
more infectious, right, and can be more
efficient when it try to affect other people,
right? It is evolving itself, OK. The similar thing
happens here with our malware. Because what
happens with malware is for each single type of the malware,
we have a signature, and sometimes we call that abstract
representation. So it's a signature of that particular type of virus.
It's like a a gene type of thing, right?
So for every person it has a different gene and gene.
And then for the virus we use that represent abstract
representation or we sometimes call signature of that particular virus type.
And then And this, this database has
all that different type of signature or abstracts in its
database. And then those database has been kept by those new
malware um generation cycle in place. It can be,
you can imagine that some um big company in the black market,
and then they're trying to generate new malware every month.
And what they do with their database is they use genetic
algorithm module to do those genes mutation,
OK, signature mutation, the crossover mutation.
They try to create a new type of signature,
right? And with this different type of signature,
with each one will be um Code, OK,
attached to those signatures and then these are the generation module and then
they are generating this code, that malware code,
and then they will output the malware to those
popular powerful different types of Uh,
antivirus software, OK. They will actually test all
those modules here, right, using this like
Capay or uh McAfee and different types. So they actually
pass through their malware to all these com companies
antivirus software and to test whether this
big antivirus software can detect. Those
malware or not. If not, they will launch to the market.
If yes, they will come back to the first mutation again
and then try to create a new type. So there's an evolving
and testing cycle for those malware. Uh,
manufacturer, right? So they try to manufacture this malware in this
cycle, only when it can't be tested or detected by
this antivirus software, and then they will be launched to the market.
Which is why this antivirus software, they
actually keep, uh, they will also keep a database of all these
signature in itself, OK, in its company's database.
And then every time when they, when they have something uh in their
database, and then they actually keep updating them,
right, every month, even every day or every week,
right? And then they have to guarantee they have found
something new in the market, and then they try to analyze what's the abstract
presentation, and then keep them in their database.
And the next time when your computer has a capacity,
antivirus software in your computer, and your computer,
OK. Because at this date, it has been updated and it
has a newer type of malware, it can detect them.
If you don't update your antivirus software,
which means you don't contain your, your soft and soft software,
don't contain those new type of Uh, malware signature.
And then your antivirus software won't be able to detect them
or delete them, right? So that's why, I mean,
we pay sometimes um monthly fee for those
capacity, for those not free uh antivirus software,
right? And then they can always give you more protection because
they update their database, um. Regularly,
and then you get better protection. And,
but of course, it also means if you have the,
the software and virus software installed in your computer,
but if you don't update them, And when there's an
update prompt, OK, you don't update them,
which actually place your computer at risk because there are new,
newer database, newer type of malware detected by
those software, by those underware software,
and you should keep updating them. Once there's a push,
OK, you should update, and then you should update,
right? So, that's why, um, There's a cycle there
and always newer type of malware being created,
but our antivirus software company and then they also try to capture them,
right? Um, but yeah, maybe one step late,
but they will, they will update, right? And then your computer as a user,
you should always keep your antivirus software updated,
OK. So, that's all for our software attack part.
And now, let's look at this web attack. OK.
There are 3 types of popular web attack.
So the very first one is a CSRF. So in step wise,
it looks like this. So you can imagine you are the victim here,
and there's a bank site, and you can sign on to your bank site.
Um, and then, during the time of your login,
and you receive an email or you found another website which is interesting,
so you just visit that website and you click on something in that website,
that website, Uh, would probably steal your cookie
and do some transaction on your behalf and send those cross-site requests,
forge the request to this bank on your behalf.
And the bank thought the request is a legitimate request from you
because that website, when they send this transaction request,
which actually contains your authentication cookie.
So authentic authentication cooking means it has your ID
encrypted, and it has your session visiting ID um probably
also encrypted. Um, and then maybe, and then,
because you logged in, and the bank won't log you out immediately.
Normally, it happens after 5 minutes if you don't do anything,
right, in your, in the, in this bank site.
So during that 5 minutes, this is what happened.
You visit another website, another website has some scripts,
uh, which can do something harmful, and then launch a
cross-site request, forge the request to this bank.
And then, so that get to tran probably transfer some money out of your account to
their account. So this can be the particular example
um in these steps. So now, the first step is to
Uh, authenticate yourself to the bank site.
So you have logged into your bank, you receive a session cookie for your
authentication. So you were in that website already,
right? And then at the same time, attacker attack,
uh, creates some malicious website this month,
and you just, uh, um, without awareness,
you during your login time. And you log into,
uh, not log in, but you just visit another website,
which is a tax website. And then there was a button,
which might be some advertisement or might be some just a lottery
running, clicking button there, and you just click that button,
and then behind the button. Which contains this
HTML language, which is a website, OK, language,
and it says this action would be done, right?
So those buttons, OK, behind the button which is this.
So transfer um some money to
To the attacker's account. And this is how much money will be transferred,
$1000 and input in the submit. So there's a
button, um, OK, you clicked, right? You
clicked and which allows this attacker's website to
utilize your cookie and then lodge
that forged request to this bank, OK?
So, That will send a request to transfer $1000 to a
tax account. And then the bank see that request
attached with your authentication cookie,
so the bank thought that request is from you,
right? So it will just, uh, yeah, I mean,
process that request, OK. So this is how it happens,
right, and then. All these CSRF request
uh forgery, um, not necessary to happen to a
bank site. It can happen to other type of site,
OK? So, this is another example, which is a social media
account. OK, and now you can imagine you visited your social media
accounts such as your Facebook account. And then the Facebook won't log
you out automatically, normally, right? So it,
it has your session cookie, which contains your unique
ID information, OK? So that it remembers you,
remembers your browser, right? And it won't log you out automatically,
normally. So then, At the same time, you
found a malicious link, of course, you don't know it's malicious.
You found a website, um, and then with an interesting clicking button,
and you click them. And what happens behind is that social
media account, um, it, it has this HTML language,
a script, and then it says change email.
It will change the email address to a new attacker's email address.
And then because you click that button and your social media email
account has been changed to the attacker's email account.
And then, so you don't know that, right?
You have, uh, there is a cross site forge request sent to
Facebook, and Facebook thought, oh, the request was from you,
and then they will just change your email.
So what happens after could be, OK, next time you log into
your Facebook account, you, you, you didn't know where your email address was changed,
so you didn't receive your six digit. Um,
authentication code and you are not able to log into a Facebook account,
right, if you have enabled two-way, like you give the password
to your, to your Facebook account you give like you ask the
Facebook also requires you to give a six digit.
Random code which was sent to your email address to log in,
OK, and then you were not able to log into your Facebook account and that's how
probably sometimes the people lost their social media account because of
this behavior, right? And what this attacker could do
is It crack your password, right?
It may, because the password is easily to be corrected if your password is not
very um secure, right, long enough, not long enough
and also has simple combination, right? Attacker correct your
password. Uh, and then the attacker has your,
has the email authentication code sent to your email,
sent to, sorry, this attacker's email. So attacker can log into your social
media account on your behalf. Because that email,
um, authentication six digit code has been sent to them.
Right, so then they can steal your account and then they can get all your friend contact list and there are
other information such as the market space,
credit card information if they are there,
and then the attacker can steal off them,
right, and can, can do some transaction as well,
right? And you can also imagine this bank.
Uh, site or social media site is an online shopping
site such as Amazon, eBay, They all possible,
right? And when you log in to Amazon or eBay,
and also at the same time, you probably won't log out,
um. I mean right after you have done your shopping,
and you probably keep, keep the login and at the same time you receive an email and
there was an interesting link and you just click the link and you are redirected to the
attacker's um website and that website you just uh
browsing something and you click something,
sometimes accidentally, right, and then your cookie,
your login, and you recognize the browser.
OK, it's still here, right? You didn't log out from your Amazon and Amazon
could, OK, um, believe there was some request
from attacker, but Amazon thought it's you,
right? And he will do probably some transaction on your behalf,
right? And they probably purchase some, some um valued
uh product for to this attacker without your
awareness, right? So. This is what happened with this cross-site
request forgery. Remember when we, um, in week one,
we look at one website which talked about all um different types of
vulnerability, and then vulnerability, there are some type,
I mean, which were CSRF if you go back to the website and
to see how many different types of vulnerability were CSRF,
which is a very main critical type of vulnerability.
Happening nowadays, right, almost every year,
right? So. So, of course, you can also think,
uh, if you log out right after you have done your shopping or
your online banking, and this cross site request forgery will be
Um, like, prevent it, right? You don't do anything when you log into
your bank. You, you do a transaction, then log out immediately after.
You don't do any other clicking or suspicious email checking and click,
uh, link clicking during that period and that cross-site record forgery
will be prevented. OK. So that's why we should always be aware of this type
of. Um, vulnerability, we shouldn't allow something
happening without our awareness, and we should always,
um, have good habits, right? And log out something if you don't
need them, and don't always keep that logged in because your session cookie can be
stolen and that can be exploited by your
Um, careless visiting or browsing on the web,
on other websites, you never know what's.
What will happen in that other website if you um,
Because even if sometimes very legitimate websites,
they also have vulnerability in that website itself,
and then the bad people could exploit those vulnerabilities and launch something
in those websites. So you never know, right?
So, and then, so this also gives us another type like this one,
XSS cross site scripting. But for CSRF,
right, for this one. As long as you make sure you log out,
and you should be safe, OK? But of course,
do a good um behavior when you do a browsing,
and then, um, make sure, yeah, the website is
probably, yeah, legitimate, at least, OK,
do not visit some fake website, right? And then always check the
URL. It's actual legitimate URL, um, but for this
CRSRF to prevent this type of vulnerability,
OK, always remember to log out. OK. But this
XSS type of web attack, which is not
something you always log out, you can prevent,
OK? So the, what, what would happen with this
XSS is attacker. They, initially,
they would explore what vulnerability a website may have,
right? And this, this is out of your control,
right? You trust some website, but however,
that website has been already launched to something in the
very first step by attacker, OK? So they discover some,
Secure hole and that website, which can be a bank site,
OK, you never know, right? The bank site itself maybe,
if not well maintained, also has this vulnerability and also
may have some injected malicious JavaScript in those
bank sites. OK, and then you don't know that,
and you visit your website, your bank site,
and you click the link and then you Accidentally
executes those malicious scripts, OK? And those scripts may
run on your computer and then may um send your
cookie to the attacker, and then this attacker may just be using
your credential and log in to this site,
OK. So this is what happened in
XSS, which is why we call that cross-site scripting attack,
OK? So it is launching this cross-site scripting attack and,
and to the site. OK, so this
is one example, uh we just show you the bank site
itself has the vulnerability in its webpage.
The scripts can steal a user's session cookie,
and then this user without knowing that,
and click the link and the cookie session is stolen,
and then this, this attacker can use that stolen
session cookie. And then the attacker can now impersonate the
victim on this bank site, right, and then it can.
can then transfer funds or change account detail or perform
other malicious action on this user's behalf,
on this victim's behalf. OK, so that's what happens in the last step.
And now let's look at these two. So what's the difference,
uh, for these two? The CSRF actually, you
can imagine. The Cross site
forged request sent to the browser, and the browser
actually trust that request, that forged the request was from
his actual user, right? So this one is actually exploiting
the trust a site has in its users, OK.
It believes that request was from that user,
OK, so it is exploiting that trust. Uh, however,
with access as exploiting the trust a user has for
a particular site. So now you can see at the very beginning,
this user, there was some, some scripts prompt,
right, and uh or injected in this bank site.
And it is exploiting that victim's trust in that bank
site. OK, so it is exploiting that, but in the
cross-site um request forgery.
It is exploiting the trust that the bank has in its
user. It always trusts all the requests were from the users.
However, there's a forged the request, uh,
cross-site request, and that the bank wasn't aware,
he still trusts the request was from his user.
So the trust, so in these two different types.
And then they are actually exploiting the trust,
um, one way or another, right? And then these are more
difference, um, for this XSS and the
CSRF, OK, different type. Uh, CSRF
is, it is causing Um, a malicious
site cause a user's browser to perform unwanted action on
the trusted website, right? And with access the malicious website
leverage bugs in a trusted website to cause unwanted action on user's
browser, right, so these are the difference and you can see the
example can all be like transfer some money or get some
authentication information and yeah, so there will be uh a
Probably at the end some money will be stolen or the credential can be
stolen, but in it's different, uh, detailed um
exploitation which is different, OK.
Um, and then another type of the web attack,
very popular one, is SQL injection attack.
OK? We call that SQL injection because SQL is a structured
query language, uh, which we use to talk to a database.
So it's very much like we, the attacker put an injection to
the SQL so that they get more information out of the
database, right? So, There's some example here I'd like to
show. Um, but before the example, I want to,
um, show some basic knowledge of the SQL language.
Um, The main thing for here is the SQL language has this
double dash, and when there's a double dash,
which means behind, OK, this double dash,
all the code will be recognized as a comment,
so which won't be, which will won't be, um,
won't be executed, OK? So all words behind the double dash
won't be executed. OK, so that's the um The
SQL language itself, right, has this, has this,
um, thing, double dash, OK, it's a, it's a common indicator.
OK, now let's see, this is a simple SQL language.
So the language itself is very simple, OK,
um, very much like humans logic language,
right, so you just select something from a database,
uh, when there is a condition satisfied.
So these are the conditions, OK. So normally when we visit websites,
for example, you visit Amazon, you want to buy some gifts for your friends,
and then. Normally you would probably in a search button,
you just search gifts, right? You, you can probably,
or you can search for another type of uh category.
Right. When we say the gifts, so what behind that
clicking, OK, uh, a search clicking, um,
is this SQL language talking to, uh, Amazon's database.
So which is to, OK, you print out all the products
when the category is gifts. And the release number is
one. So when the, when the product is released or is in stock,
or release equals to one means maybe you have them in stock,
or it has been released and ready for sale,
right? So release is one and then category is gifts,
OK, you just print out all those products and then the user can,
can browse all the products and then pick one,
right. However, If A user
or the attacker wants to get more out of this gifts,
what they can do is they just put something like this,
OK, in their, in their, um, Searching,
OK, what they can do is they just put a gift and single comma and double dash
behind. So they just put this text in those text search box,
OK. Then it will change the logic for this language for the
SQL line code. OK, what it will be changed to
is select something from products where this condition
are satisfied, right, so the condition is category is gifts,
right, and then this single comma and double commas.
So then this condition. Does not matter anymore.
So that means this condition is not needed.
So it will be just recognized as a comment,
OK. So, it won't be executed, right? So then that
language original here has become this one,
OK, up to here. So that means the category is gifted,
you just print them all out, OK, no matter if it's
released or not. So even if it's not
released, all gifts will be printed out.
OK, you can see all the database, uh, as long as the category is gifts,
no matter it's released or not released.
So that double, um double dash has come
out this condition. OK? So what you can even do
more is you change some logic. Um, yeah,
you, you, you actually can do some union and you can do something
else. So now this is another example, OK.
There's some login system, OK, and then there's the email address or
username, a username, um, which is administrator,
and a password, you just give a password.
So what normally The, the conditions
should be you give the right username, you give the right password,
OK, the username should be administrator and the password is a secret,
and then click log in and then you can log in,
right? So that's how it should work, OK,
if everything is properly designed. However,
because you know there's a security hole and you know
this one, OK, will all be taken by the SQL language
and then so you just put a single comma,
double dash and then now you can see you select something from
user where username is administrator and then all the
behind, OK, behind this were commented
out. So it doesn't matter the password is given or not
correctly or not, and as long as you put an administrator you can bypass the
system. You can log into the system, right?
So that allows this condition to be satisfied and you can go to
the system, right? So. That's one example with
this double dash. So now you can see the problem
is with this system's um developer, right?
And then they allowed all this string to be recognized to
be input as a valid input, right, as a valid uh
text. So, um, How do we prevent,
at least this one can be prevented by using.
Parameterized the query, OK, you can use the prepared
statements, uh, instead of string concatenation within the
queries, you don't allow those strings to be recognized.
You don't, you do more sanitization, right?
You, you, you, or you just, uh, um, allow drop down box,
OK, for example, that gifts, you don't allow them,
uh, users to input something extra and you don't recognize them.
And then you just allow um Parameterize the
query and you only allow like gifts, OK,
um, appliance or certain type of, uh, drop down
box, OK. Only allow those to be input to this box and
then, and then user has no way to, to add something or
even change other logic like put some or condition,
um. Yeah, so that it get, can get more information out of the
database. So this is a SQL injection attack.
OK. So now, let's see.
More, OK, uh, hardware threats. So web attacks,
mainly these three types. I hope now you have an idea what each type is.
Um, in, in my week one, website, I think you've
seen those different types of vulnerability,
and all those three types of vulnerability are actually meant.
Type OK, among all of those increasing vulnerability each year.
And then the hardware threats, there are 4 types of hardware and there's 3 categories
of threats. And now I think all the information here are quite obvious
and straightforward. So there are environmental threats,
technical threats. Um, and also human
caused threats, right? And human cause threats
can include those um different types of,
yeah, reason, OK. So, these are all about
hardware. And then what are emergent threats?
Emergence threats can happen to those IOT devices
and can have those botnets leveraging IOT and
which can be a distributed service attack,
right? And, um, better malware, and you know,
now know why we always have better malware.
Um, but of course, antivirus software, uh,
those companies also are working very hard to update their database,
right? To capture those better malware. And then there are also state
sponsored threats, um, and some new
devices, uh, or connected, exposing
the risks and most of them, I mean, the firmware are not
like updated very well. And no more corporate
network means our environment changed recently,
in, especially in these five years, right?
Most small businesses, they just choose cloud service,
they don't maintain their own server. And most of this,
I mean, different type of like university,
institution, they just allow you to bring your own device,
BYOD bring your own device, which actually pose
extra risk to this company network or the university
network. Like Griffiths allows you to bring your own laptop,
then that also actually puts the Griffiths at risk because your laptop,
if not maintained very well, can infect.
The computers within the same subnet as your computer.
OK, um, And which, yeah, which, um,
gives more flexibility, but, however, uh,
gives more threats to our cyberspace. And how to prevent.
Um, I think you've already had some idea when you get to know those
different types of attacks, but these are more Um,
OK, tips here. Um, use clean software apps,
uh, whether those software are clean or
not, and there's a way to check. And whether,
um, antivirus software is reputable or not,
and actually you can. Uh, use some websites to judge whether
it's reputable or not. Um, actually, this one,
we will actually do that some practice, I think,
in, um, the following weeks, and you can check whether
Uh, software is clean or not, OK, through those websites.
And you can also check if there's a malware.
And you give the signature or hash value to the to
the website. And then some antivirus software can detect
them, but some of them don't. OK? Then you can judge,
oh, which one is more reputable. Because some existing
signature, OK, those big company and maybe they can detect
them, but those free antivirus software cannot,
right? And then you better not use those not reputable antivirus
software, because we, we've seen those results from the website.
You get a chance to practice this, OK, during your workshop.
Um, so this is an example. I give you some hash and for you to
examine whether that hash, OK, that can be recognized,
I mean, understood as a signature of, of,
of a virus, and then, And then you give to the website,
ask the website to analyze for you, and then you can see at least all different types
of um antivirus software whether they have been able to
detect that malware or not. Right? And then you know,
OK, which antivirus software may be better than others,
OK? So we will, we will detect them, we,
uh, we will try to practice them in our,
uh, workshop. OK, of course, there are some more
tips, which maybe you know most of them.
And um as we go through the course, we will probably
also show you how to secure your home router and which encryption algorithm
is better than other, right? And then when you learn the
cryptography, cryptography in next week and the week after,
we have 2 weeks to learn cryptography, and you understand how Uh,
which is a better encryption algorithm. OK,
so, um, that's all the email tips. I
won't read them out, you can read them by yourself,
right? Um, but I think many of them probably you know,
but there are also some, some items may be uh worthwhile to read through,
and um, yeah. To get better uh habit when we
use email. And then, so this is about arrangement for
this week and next week, and we have workshop in this week.
Um, so I'm expecting you have received that as
your invitation link, OK, for you to register an
account, right? And if not, please contact your
tutor, uh, in your workshop, if you have issue when you register,
and we will try to, um, try to help you in our workshop.
And if you enrolled late to the course, please do reach out to
the tutor according to the, uh, I mean, the,
the, the announcement I've already made,
OK, this morning. OK, so that's all for today.
Thanks for your attention and we'll do more in your workshop,
OK. Thank you. Any question?
No question. OK, for now, yeah. So if you
have questions, please um ask us through Teams,
OK? Thanks.